LOUIS SAVOIE

1(517)392-5239 • thttps://www.louissavoie.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/lou-savoie • https://github.com/louissavoie

Self-taught programmer looking to transfer twenty years of retail experience into a career in software engineering. I am a motivated self-starter and an engaged team player. I'd bring a new perspective and a

natural curiosity to your team. ------

RELEVANT PROJECTS

rpu

Built with Bootstrap, EJS, Node.js, Express, MongoDB

Full-Stack Web App

- Users create a character and give it skills that they want to develop in real life. After practicing their skills, they make a post about it and their character levels increase.
- Keeps users engaged with the skill building process using reward mechanics.

Create Project

Built for Linux with Bash and Ruby

Git Repository Creation Script

- One command creates a GitHub repository, a local Git repository, a README file and an initial commit, pushes to the remote, and opens the project in VSCode.
- Automates the creation of new projects, saving time and focus.

YouTube Crossposter

Built with Node.js

Automated Video Crossposter

- Uses a crontabs schedule to automatically retrieve the most recent video data from a YouTube channel, check if the data is new, and then post the data to a subreddit.
- Automates marketing of your videos, saving time and eliminating soul-crushing work.

Puppet Intern Scraper

Built with Ruby

Web Scraper Script

- Scrapes and parses HTML from the <u>Puppet jobs page</u>, searches for the substring "intern", then prints the list of job postings and highlights intern positions, if posted.
- Makes the information more digestible by presenting it in an easier to read format.

EDUCATION

Self-Directed Learning

2020 - Present

APIs • SEO • OpenGraph • Git • Github • Ruby(Basics) • Linux • VSCode • Sass(Basics)

Udemy 2021

The Web Developer Bootcamp by Colt Steele

HTML(Intermediate) • CSS(Intermediate) • Javascript(Intermediate) • DOM • Bootstrap • EJS Node.js • Express • REST • NoSQL • Mongoose • MongoDB • User Auth • Deployment • Heroku

University of Helsinki Massive Open Online Courses

2020

Object-Oriented Programming with Java

IDEs • Java • Object-Oriented Programming

WORK HISTORY

Polly's Country Market - Produce Clerk/Stand-in Manager

Meijer - Grocery/GM/Produce Team Member

Burger King - Safety Coordinator

2013 - Present

7 Years 9 Months

7 Years 10 Months

2005 - 2013

3 Years 7 Months